Windy.com Privacy Policy
========================

We appreciate that you value your privacy and the protection of your data as much as we do and are pleased to present the Windy.com Privacy Policy. We have designed our privacy policy and the manner in which we handle user data entrusted to us by our valued users in our [community.windy.com](http://community.windy.com/) (“**Community**”), or who use our _Windy.com_ mobile app or visit our website [windy.com](http://windy.com/) (“**App**” and “**Website**”), and/or make use of our other online services (in particular [Windy Stations](https://stations.windy.com/) or [Windy API](https://api.windy.com/) and other) (all the services of Windy.com jointly as “**Services**”), to be as honest and transparent as possible. We are committed to ensure full compliance with all applicable legislation, including the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) by the European Union at all levels of our Services.

We consider these points to be the cornerstone takeaways for you to know:

* Our main reason for storing user data is only **to ensure the proper functionality and a better user experience of our service** and related online services.
    
* **We will never sell your personal data to third parties**. Although certain data needs to be shared with key partners, such as server hosting providers, and we also share it for our other legitimate business purposes, such as analytics services, we have ensured that all such partners also meet all GDPR standards.
    
* We are continuously implementing the very latest technologies to ensure that **all data is always stored in a safe manner** according to the latest security standards.

We kindly encourage you to read our privacy policy below to learn what data we collect and why. Your continued faith in us is of utmost importance. Should you have any questions related to our privacy policy, please do not hesitate to contact us in one of the ways described in the “Contacts” section below.

General information
-------------------

1. This Privacy Policy (“**Privacy Policy**”) regulates how we use, process and handle your personal data, and how you can exercise your rights regarding your personal data.
    
2. This Privacy Policy also provides you with all of the necessary information according to the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“**GDPR**”) with respect to all Services.
    
    Chapter 3 of this Privacy Policy applies to the respective Services as per each heading in the chapter. All other chapters provide information which is common to all Services. If Chapter 3 provides information which is different from the information provided in other general chapters, the more specific information provided in Chapter 3 applies.
    
3. In this Privacy Policy, the following definitions are used:
    
    * “**Community**” means our community forum at [community.windy.com](https://community.windy.com/).
        
    * “**Company**”, “**we**” means **Windyty, SE** (known as Windy or Windy.com), having its registered office at Strakonická 3363/2d, 150 00 Prague 5, Czech Republic, registered in the Commercial Register kept by the Municipal Court in Prague, Section H, Insert 1671, ID No.: 046 41 647.
        
    * “**Services**” means any of the services, applications, and websites operated by the Company and made available to you. Currently, we operate and provide, in particular, the following Services:
        
        * Windy Website and the App (compatible with Android, iOS, and other selected systems and devices, including smart watches)
        * Community portal Windy Community ([community.windy.com](http://community.windy.com/))
        * Windy Stations services ([stations.windy.com](https://stations.windy.com/))
        * Windy API through which specific functionalities are accessed ([api.windy.com](https://api.windy.com/))
        * Service allowing sharing the webcams pictures/videos
    * “**User**”, “**you**” means the person, company or institution that uses the Services.
        
4. We are the controller of your personal data.

Services we provide and the general scope of processing of personal data
------------------------------------------------------------------------

1. Services. The company provides a global weather tracking and forecasting application, which can be customized to a certain extent according to Users’ preferences on their own devices through the Website and the App. The Users may also contribute to the Services by adding their own camera and/or weather station, which will then provide more relevant local information to us as well as to other users. The Users may also decide to register, and in such case, personal settings are saved in the profile and synchronized across devices used with that account. The Windy Stations, and API Services are provided only to registered users. The content shared through the Community Service can also be accessed by non-registered Users, but only after registration any content can be added. The Services are offered both for free and for subscription. Users with subscription can use a wider range of tools and are offered with extra features such as 1-hour forecast view, 10-day forecast outlook, forecast updates at least 4 times a day, more detailed forecast maps, unlimited Favorites and Alerts, 12-hour loop for Radar and Satellite, Satellite archive and many others as currently offered and provided.
    
2. Legal grounds for personal data processing. Our processing of your personal data will typically be based on one of the following processing legal bases:
    
    * because we need to process your data in order **to provide you with the Services** or a particular feature of the Services, i.e. to perform our contract (meaning also an informal relationship) with you. You can find the full wording of the contract/relationship you conclude with us by using the Services in respective Terms of Use (accessible via our website);
        
    * because such processing is necessary for the purposes of the **legitimate interests** pursued either by us or by a third party and such legitimate interests are not overridden by your privacy or related rights as an individual. Our legitimate interests include e.g. the necessary maintenance of our infrastructure, statistical analysis of the use of the Services, and protection of our legally protected rights;
        
    * because we are legally obliged to do so, for example, we are called upon to disclose your personal data to **public authorities**; or
        
    * because you have provided us with your specific, informed, freely-given, and unambiguous consent; we may periodically **ask for your further consent** to use your personal data for certain specific reasons.
        
3. Scope of processed personal data. In order to provide and maximize your experience with the Services, we may need to collect and use certain information from our Users, some of which could be considered ‘personal data’ within the meaning of the GDPR or other relevant privacy legislation applicable in your country. If we can use the information, alone or in combination, to reasonably identify you as an individual, we treat the information as personal data.
    
    Please note that you may choose to provide us with certain **optional or additional information** when you interact with the Services, in particular, in the following ways:
    
    * Send us an **email message** to receive additional information – for example, you might email us with a question and we will use your email address to respond to your inquiry;
        
    * **Submit a comment or other content** like feedback and suggestions to make our services more accurate or valid (e.g. reports relating to webcams such as wrong location, poor image quality, other issue, etc. – such information is manually reviewed), or send us a photo or video – for example, you might submit a cool photo of a weather event you experienced that we may post on the Services so others can enjoy it.
        
        Special Note about Content Submissions. The Services may offer areas (**community, articles**) where you and other users can post or otherwise submit information, photos, videos, graphics, creative suggestions, ideas, notes, concepts, information, ratings, or other materials on or to the Services (collectively, "**Submissions**"). Any geolocation information, tags, or other metadata in such Submissions may become publicly available. Any information, including personal data, in your Submissions can be read, collected and used by others. We cannot control and are not responsible for how others may use the information contained in your Submissions;
        
    * **Customize the Services** – for example, you might set a "**home" location** so that every time you visit the Services, you automatically receive a display of the weather for that home location.

    _This data is provided by you to the extent you wish to benefit from the respective functionalities of our Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
    
    The extent to which we process personal data in general depends on whether you use the Windy Services as a registered **or non-registered user**.
    
4. General processing personal data of all Users (both registered and non-registered)
    
    1. **Statistical and measurement data.** In addition to the processing of your personal data as outlined for the particular Services in Chapter 3 below, we generally process your personal data also for statistical and analytical purposes.
        
        We also collect statistical and measurement data through automated means from Google Analytics. Although the data present in Google Analytics reports is anonymized and we are not able to associate it with you, please note that Google itself collects your IP address. More information about Google Analytics can be found [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). For the similar reasons we also use other services, such as BigQuery (more information about Google BigQuery can be found [here](https://cloud.google.com/bigquery/docs/data-governance)).
        
        For example, we automatically collect:
        
        * Information about your device and device capabilities;
        * Information about your device’s operating system;
        * Information about your browser;
        * Information about how you use the Services;
        * Your activities on the Services;
        * Mobile or internet carrier/provider;
        * Browser type;
        * Browser identifier;
        * Referring URL.
        
        This information helps us to understand, analyze, and measure how users use the Services; manage the Services' operations; diagnose problems; recognize repeat visitors; and facilitate your access to and use of the Services.
        
        _The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract and our legitimate interest in the effective operation, enhancement and further development of the Services._
        
    2. **Third party technologies** that we use in our infrastructure can produce technical logs with your IP address; we do not perform any analysis or data mining with this data (and delete it regularly, usually after one month). If any personal data is processed (your IP address), such data is used only to operate and improve such technologies.

    _The processing legal basis for this purpose is such third party’s legitimate interest in operating and improving their technologies._
    
5. Processing personal data of registered Users only
    
    1. **User account registration:** When you choose to register a user account, you will be required to provide your email address and username.
        
        This data is provided by you if you wish to create a user account and benefit from the respective functionalities of our Website and the App (or our [Community](http://community.windy.com/) site and other Services – please see further chapters). We also use it to communicate with you in this regard.
        
        _The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
        _We may further use this data to analyze, improve, enhance, and fine-tune our products and the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing the Services._
        
    2. **Social Login via Facebook, Google or Apple.** You can register a user account or log in by linking your Facebook, Google or Apple account via a service called Social Login, which is an easy, secure, and straightforward way to register with us or log in into our Services quickly.
        
        If you connect Facebook, Google or Apple to your Windy account, we will use your name, profile picture and email address for registration and authentication purposes so you can benefit from the respective functionalities of our [Community](http://community.windy.com/) site and other Services. We also use it to communicate with you in this regard.
        
        _The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
        We may further use this data, and some of your other public information from these accounts, to analyze, improve, enhance, and fine-tune our products and the Services.
        
        _The processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing the Services._
        
        When using Social Login services via Apple/Google/Facebook account on the Website or in the App, the Company collects and processes your personal information from the company Apple Inc. (name, email address, language setting and profile photo), Google, Inc. (name, email address, language setting and profile photo) or Meta Platforms, Inc. (name, email address and profile photo) for the purpose of user account registration/log-in.
        
        The amount of information we are able to access is dependent on the privacy policy and the settings of your third-party accounts. These settings, in a combination with what Windy asks for, determines the extent of the data that can be accessed. Windy account can be disconnected from the linked third-party account at any time. For more information about Social Login, please follow our community article: [information-about-user-profile](https://community.windy.com/topic/20330/information-about-user-profile).
        
    3. **Marketing.** We may also use your email address for direct marketing. If we send you electronic marketing messages based on our legitimate interest or as otherwise permitted by applicable law, you may, at any time, declare your objection. Any electronic marketing messages you receive from us will include an opt-out mechanism within the message itself, e.g. an ‘unsubscribe’ link in the email you receive from us.

The extent to which we process your personal data further depends on **what Services** you use – please see below in Chapter 3 more details relating to processing operations pertinent to particular Windy Services.

Processing of personal data within the individual Services
----------------------------------------------------------

The text in this Chapter 3 below summarizes the ways in which we collect your personal data, what categories of personal data we collect and use, the purposes for which we process your personal data, and the legal bases for such processing purposes with regard to each individual Service we offer. The information provided in this chapter applies specifically to the respective Service and it is complementary to the general information provided in other chapters.

1. **Windy Webpage and App – including webcam registration functionality**
    
    The Webpage and App can be used by both registered as well as non-registered users. The scope of processing of your personal data then differs accordingly.
    
    1. _Processing personal data of **all Users** (both registered and non-registered)_
        
        If you use our Services (Webpage and App) as a non-registered user, only statistical and measurement data (see Chapter 2.4.1. above) are processed. All of your favorites, search history and settings are stored solely inside your device, and never transferred to our servers.
        
        Further, we collect the following data:
        
        1. Whenever the App or Webpage crash, a **crash message** is sent to our server for investigation (and deleted after one month).
            
            The processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in improving our Services.
            
        2. **Geographic area-related services.** The Webpage and the App offer you quick access to weather-related information on your mobile device (e.g. Widget), and other geographic area-related weather information can be accessed on your desktop or mobile device (e.g. Radar). To provide these Services, we need to collect and use information on your current location (through the GPS module in your device or your IP address). If you no longer wish to share your GPS location with our Services, you may change the settings within your mobile device or not to allow us to use your current location when the Services would require this information. If you refuse to share your precise GPS location, the Services will then be geographically approximated according to your current IP address.

        _This data is provided by you to the extent you wish to benefit from the respective functionalities of our Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
    2. _Processing personal data of registered Users only_
        
        Should you register yourself to the Services – Website or the App (other Services such as Community site, Windy Stations, Windy API, etc. are described in separate chapters), and depending on the extent in which you will use our Services, besides the general processing operation we will carry out with respect to registered users (please see Chapters 2.5.1. through 2.5.3.) in relation to Website or the App, we will also process the following information, which may qualify as personal data.
        
        1. **Your Favorites, Search History and Settings on our servers.**
            
            _This data is provided by you to the extent you wish to benefit from the respective functionalities of our Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
            
            _We may further use this data to analyze, improve, enhance, and fine-tune our products and the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing the Services._
            
        2. **Alerts and Notifications_._** Certain Services offer you the ability to receive weather-related updates via email or as a mobile notification. To provide these Services, we need to collect your email address, the geographic area to which the alert updates shall pertain and information about devices that you use. If you no longer wish to receive these notifications, you may opt out by turning them off within the alert settings of your user account, through the settings on your mobile device or the particular Service for which you registered, or by using the unsubscribe link provided directly in your email alert.
            
            _This data is provided by you to the extent you wish to benefit from the respective functionalities of our Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
            
        3. **Webcam registration** _(Possible also for non-registered users, however, **registration is highly recommended**)_.

        You may also register a webcam using the URL and location of the webcam and your email address.
        
        Within the framework of the Services offered by the Provider, personal data may be provided by you to the extent that you wish to benefit from the corresponding functionality of the Services. Specifically, the following personal data are processed:
        
        * Webcam Operators’ personal data. During the webcam registration, operators are offered the possibility to enter their webcam page's URL, location, and the station operator’s name.
            
        * The data and content posted through the webcam may be shared with us and/or with other users of the Services or used only as private (i.e. only accessible to users with specific link) depending on your setting of the device in the course of its registration.

        _This data is provided by the operator if they wish to incorporate a webcam to the Windy Website and/or the App and benefit from the respective functionalities of the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
        _We may further use this data to analyze, improve, enhance and fine-tune the products and the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is a legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing the Services._
        
2. **Windy Community**
    
    Windy Community is a community forum used to share content and communicate between us and the users as well as among the users themselves.
    
    1. **User account registration** – please see general Chapter 2.5.1.
        
        You can also register a user account by linking your Facebook, Google or Apple account via a service called Social Login **Social Login**, which is an easy, secure, and straightforward way to register with us or log in into our Service quickly. In such case we process your related personal data as outlined in general Chapter 2.5.2. above.
        
        This data is provided by you if you wish to create a user account and benefit from the respective functionalities of our [Community](http://community.windy.com/) site. We also use it to communicate with you in this regard. Occasionally, we may send emails to your registered email address in order to provide updates and/or to notify you of new activity that is pertinent to you. You can customize the frequency of the community digest (including disabling it outright), as well as select which types of notifications to receive via email, via your user settings page. Unless explicitly changed in your user settings, this community does not send out email digests.
        
        _The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
    2. **Content Submissions.** The Community offers areas where you and other users can post or otherwise submit information, photos, videos, graphics, creative suggestions, ideas, notes, concepts, information, ratings, or other materials on or to the Service. If you decide to do so, your personal data are processed as outlined in general Chapter 2.3 above.
        
3. **Windy Stations**
    
    Service enabling Users to register their personal or professional Weather Station, sharing their data, seeing them on Windy and eventually also sharing them with others as Open Data.
    
    1. **Weather station registration.** Once you are logged in, you may also register a weather station using the location and other details of the station. Within the framework of the Services offered by the Provider, personal data may be provided by you to the extent that you wish to benefit from the corresponding functionality of the Services. Specifically, the following personal data are processed:
        
        * _Station Operators’ personal data._ During the station registration, operators are offered the possibility to enter their station and/or webcam page's URL, location and other details, as well as the station operator’s name.
            
        * The data and content posted through the weather station may be shared with us and/or with other users of the Services or used only as private (i.e. only accessible to users with specific link) depending on your setting of the device in the course of its registration.

        _This data is provided by the operator if they wish to incorporate a station and benefit from the respective functionalities of the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
        _We may further use this data to analyze, improve, enhance and fine-tune the products and the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is a legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing the Services._
        
4. **Windy API**
    
    Windy API enables users to obtain certain machine-readable data relating to weather monitoring and forecast. Windy provides several types of API, such as:
    
    * Point Forecast – data regarding the weather forecast for a specified set of coordinates;
    * Map Forecast – enables adding Windy maps to third party’s website;
    * Webcams API – enables adding webcams and their content to third party’s websites.
    
    This service is only accessible to registered users (please see the information on how we handle personal data during **user account registration** and **social login** in general Chapters 2.6 and 2.7. Should you wish to use the API Services, you need to sign up and generate your API key. In this case we process the following information, which may qualify as your personal data:
    
    1. **API key generating.** To generate an API key, you will be required to provide the URL of your project or ID of your application.
        
        _This data is provided by you to the extent that you wish to benefit from the respective functionalities of our Services and to communicate with you in this regard. The processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._
        
        _We may further use this data to provide the Services, and to analyze, improve, enhance, and fine tune our products and the Services. The processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in operating, enhancing and further developing of the Services._
        
        **Services interaction.** You may also choose to provide us with information, some of which may be personal data, when you interact with the Services. The processing of this data provides you with a better user experience. For further details please see general Chapter 2.3 optional or additional information.
        
    2. **Automatically Collected Information.** We automatically collect information regarding you and your interactions with us, your use of the Services, as well as information regarding your computer or other devices used to access the Services. This information may include the **traffic of your activities on the Services**; **IP address** from where the API request originated; and/or **user agent information**.
        
        _This information helps us to understand, analyze, and measure how Users use the Services; manage the Services' operations; help diagnose problems; and improve, enhance, and fine-tune our Services – the processing legal basis for this purpose is our legitimate interest in the effective operation of the Services._
        
        _This information also allows us to facilitate your access to and deliver the Services pursuant to your requests - the processing legal basis for this purpose is the performance of a contract._

Recipients of your personal data
--------------------------------

1. The personal data we collect within all Services is mainly disclosed to selected **employees** of our Company. The access of these employees to your personal data is limited and these employees may access your personal data only to the extent necessary to carry out the obligations arising from their work.
    
2. Personal data collected with regard to purchases you make in our Services (**subscription**) is controlled by third parties based on agreements we have concluded with such parties. These service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information and correspond with the GDPR. In the case that the third party shares certain data with us that might be considered personal, we are the controller of your personal data and process it on the legal basis of our legitimate interest to know the identity of the purchaser, e.g. in the case of any complaints raised by the purchaser about their subscription.
    
3. Some of your personal data may be disclosed to **tax authorities**, criminal law authorities and, to a certain extent, also to other public authorities. We will share your personal data when we, in good faith, believe it is necessary for us to do so in order to comply with legal obligations under applicable law, or respond to valid legal processes.
    
4. We may also share your personal data where we, in good faith, believe that it is necessary for the purposes of our own or a third party’s legitimate interest relating to law enforcement, litigation and/or criminal investigation, provided that we deem that such interest is not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms requiring the protection of your personal data.
    
5. Your email address that we use for **emailing you** may be shared with providers of such emailing services provided that your email address cannot be used for any purpose other than the purpose of informing you about the latest news, projects or updates in our Services. The legal basis for such sharing is our legitimate interest in outsourcing certain technological services.
    
6. Your personal data may be uploaded onto third party **servers** belonging to providers **of analytical functionalities** that we use for the processing of your data provided that your personal data cannot be used for any other purpose than the purpose of improving our services. The legal basis for such sharing is our legitimate interest in improving our services.
    
7. In order to enable users throughout the world to access our Services, it is necessary for us to use **third party servers** to provide the proper functioning of our Services. However, even with the use of such server providers, your personal data is secured in compliance with the GDPR. The legal basis for such sharing is the performance of a contract and our legitimate interest in providing our services effectively.
    
8. To ensure that you receive the greatest privacy guarantees and data protection assurances we can provide, **we carefully review all third parties with which we cooperate**. Our third-party service providers do not have any right to use the information we share with them beyond what is necessary for them to assist us in the provision of the Services.
    
9. **Information from fan pages on social networks**
    
    Within our services, we have certain buttons and tools of the social networks Facebook, Instagram, Reddit, VK and Twitter. Additionally, we are also active on LinkedIn, YouTube, Buffer, Pinterest and Tumblr. We never process personal or other visitor fan data in any way other than the settings of the individual social networks allow or for purposes for which the user has given their consent.
    
    Content delivered to the mentioned fan pages by users (e.g. comments under articles) is primarily the responsibility of the individual users or the operator of the social network; however, if you send a warning about the objectionable content of such posts, we will properly address it.
    
    On our fan site, we only hear about you if the information is provided by the social networking site or you personally, if you comment on or flag any of our articles or content or send us a message. We do not enrich your information in any way with your profile data on that network.
    
10. **International transfer of personal data**
    
    The Company is a corporation established in the Czech Republic but it operates globally. Therefore, in the course of provision of the Services, your personal data will be processed in the Czech Republic but also in other states from where we or our partners operate, namely Germany, USA and Taiwan.
    
    If you are user from outside of the Czech Republic, when you use our Services, your personal data will be transferred as follows:
    
    * **Recipient (Contact Information):** Windyty, SE ([dataprotection@windy.com](mailto:dataprotection@windy.com))
    * **Country to which it is transferred:** Czech Republic
    * **Date, time and method of transfer:** Transmitted through network at the point of service use
    * **Items of personal information transferred:** All your personal information created and collected during your use of the service (as described in Chapter 2 _“Services we provide and the general scope of processing of personal data”_ and Chapter 3 _“Processing of personal data within the individual Services”_)
    * **Recipient's purpose of use:** Provision of services, maintenance of related systems, statistical analysis, legitimate interest
    * **Period of retention and use by recipient:** Retained and used until membership is withdrawn or for the statutory retention period (unless otherwise specified in Chapter 5).
    
    We transfer your personal data to our partners who provide us with hosting services and with the related infrastructure and we do so solely for the purpose of provision of the Services. We do not sell to or otherwise share your personal data with any third party for purposes such as marketing.
    
    Whenever we transfer your personal data to any third party established outside of the European Union, we take measures to ensure that these third parties protect personal data in accordance with the GDPR. Such measures include either conclusion of the Standard Contractual Clauses issued by the European Commission or other tools as envisaged by the GDPR.

How long do we store your personal data
---------------------------------------

1. We only store your personal data **for as long as is necessary to provide you with the Services and for legitimate and essential business purposes**, such as analyzing the performance of the Services, making data-driven business decisions about new features in our Services. We never use for these business purposes personal data which are older than four years since they were collected (relates to both registered as well as non-registered users), or, in the case of registered users, older than one year from deleting user account (whichever period is longer). We may use older data for analytical and statistical purposes after they are anonymized. We might also store your personal data for the period necessary for us to comply with our legal obligations, and protecting our legal interests.
    
2. We retain your personal data for the life of your user account. You may discontinue your account anytime via “Edit Profile” (on the Community webpage) or “My Profile” (within other Services).
    
3. If you delete your account, your individual profile will be discontinued, although your posted content will remain. If you wish to delete both your account and your content, please [contact us](mailto:dataprotection@windy.com).
    
4. Beyond the periods indicated above we do not process your personal data unless we are legally allowed or required to maintain certain personal data, including in situations such as the following:
    
    * To the extent that we are required to do so by law (e.g. for our legal, tax, audit, and accounting obligations).
        
    * If we believe that the data may be relevant to any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings or dispute, or in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention), which is our legitimate interest.
        
    * Where necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as maintaining the security of our system.

How we secure your personal data
--------------------------------

1. Privacy and security are key considerations in the creation and delivery of our Services. We take appropriate steps to address online security, physical security, risk of data loss and other such risks taking into consideration the risk represented by the processing and the nature of the data being protected. Also, we limit access to our databases containing personal data to only authorized persons having a justified need to access such information.

Your rights
-----------

1. We hereby inform you that you have, as available and except as limited under applicable law, the following rights under the GDPR in relation to your personal data:
    
    1. **Right to access your personal data.** You have the right to access personal data about you that we have collected. You can do so by contacting us using the contact details indicated below.
        
    2. **Right to rectification of personal data.** You have the right to request that we rectify or amend incorrect or incomplete personal data about you that we have collected. You can do so by contacting us using the contact details indicated below.
        
    3. **Right to erasure of personal data.** You have the right to request that we erase all of your personal data that we have collected during your use of our Services. The process of doing so for registered Users is fully automated within the Services by providing you the possibility of deleting your account (or _ad hoc_ deleting your content from the Community). If you want to do so, you will find the detailed instructions [here](https://account.windy.com/profile/delete). If you are a non-registered User or if you encounter any issues with the deletion of your account, email us and we will try to help you with the execution of your request.
        
    4. **Right to restriction of processing of personal data.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data in certain cases until your request that we erase or change your personal data or other objection is processed.
        
    5. **Right to portability of your personal data.** You have the right to request that we give you the personal data that you have provided to us if such data has been processed based on your consent or based on a contract concluded with us and such personal data has been processed by automated means. If you make such request, we will provide you with all of your personal data that we collected in a structured machine-readable form. You are also entitled to request that we transfer such personal data to a new controller if it is technically possible.
        
    6. **Right to object to the processing of your personal data.** If you feel that the processing of your personal data based on our legitimate interest is not proportional to your rights, you can object to such processing and request that we provide you with compelling legitimate grounds for such processing.
        
    7. **Right to object to your personal data being processed for direct marketing purposes.** If we send you electronic marketing messages based on your consent or as otherwise permitted by applicable law, you may, at any time, withdraw such consent or declare your objection. Any electronic marketing messages you receive from us will include an opt-out mechanism within the message itself, e.g. an ‘unsubscribe’ link in the email you receive from us.
        
    8. **Right to withdraw your consent to process your personal data.** Should we have processed your personal data based on your consent, you can withdraw such consent at any time by emailing us with such a request to do so or by other means enabled within our Services. Please note that such withdrawal will not affect the legality of the processing of your personal data made prior to such withdrawal.
        
    9. **Right to file a complaint.** You can contact and have the right to lodge a complaint with the Czech Data Protection Authority ([www.uoou.cz](http://www.uoou.cz/)) or your local Data Protection Authority.
        
2. You have the right to change or update any inaccurate data provided to us via editing your profile (applies for users registered at Windy Community or other Windy Services). Your profile can be updated by editing your profile, and post content can always be edited.
    
3. Right to access, erasure, data portability or withdrawing consent to certain personal data processed when using the Community can be exercised at [https://community.windy.com/me/consent](https://community.windy.com/me/consent).
    
4. In relation to API Services you can exercise some of your data subject rights at the [api.windy.com](https://api.windy.com/) website via Manage API keys.
    
5. In order to exercise your rights and in addition to the means described above, you are welcome contact us in one of the ways described in the Chapter 8 “Contacts” below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable period of time, however not later than within one month from our receipt of your request (this period may be extended by two further months where necessary).

Contacts
--------

1. If you have a question about data protection or you want to send us any suggestions in this area, please use the email address [dataprotection@windy.com](mailto:dataprotection@windy.com) to contact us. Department in charge of data protection and handling personal information complaints is our “Administrative Department”.
    
2. You can also send us a letter to the address of our registered office mentioned in the “General information” section of this Privacy Policy.

Final provisions
----------------

1. We may periodically change this Privacy Policy or change, modify, or withdraw access to this site at any time, with or without prior notice. We are committed to keeping you informed about how your personal data is being handled. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you as appropriate under the circumstances, e.g. **by sending you an email or by displaying a notice on the [Website](http://www.windy.com/) or on our [Community](http://community.windy.com/) page or in the App.**
